allcatalogues.co.za 2018-02-02

# Privacy Policy

**1\. General terms.**

Prospecto group JSC develops the platform of allcatalogues.co.za. Our main goal is to help users quickly and easily to find the latest promotions in their city. Users can visit the website knowing that their personal information is fully protected. Prospecto group JSC does not collect personal data such as names, credit card numbers, addresses, etc. We use the generated information mainly for statistical purposes. This allows us to continuously optimize and modify the site according to the requirements and interests of the users.

**2\. Allcatalogues.co.za Cookies Policy**

Cookies are small pieces of text that Internet sites store in your computer through your web browser. Their use started in the mid 90s, and at the moment Cookies represent one of the most globally used Internet technologies.  They cannot spread viruses or grant access to your hard disk though. Therefore, we cannot read any information stored in your hard disk even if it stores cookies as well.

The basic website functions rely on Cookies. Thanks to them, information and online ads are received which you will most probably find interesting or appropriate. On the other hand, with no Cookies you cannot shop online because Cookies are used for storing the items you select in your shopping cart.

The cookies used in Allcatalogues.co.za do not collect any of your personal information or any other kind of personal details, and they cannot cause any harm to your personal computer, tablet or mobile phone. We use Cookies to grant you optimal Internet use and, on the other hand, to enhance the efficiency and functionality of the website. This section of our privacy policy provides clear and comprehensive information on the Cookies we use as well as on the purposes we use them for.

**What information will be stored by a Cookie?**

Usually a Cookie stores:

  * The URL of the website it comes from;
  * Expiry of the Cookie or the period of time it will stay on your personal computer or phone;
  * Value – usually a randomly generated unique number.

How long do Cookies stay on your computer?

  * Session cookies – these Cookies are on until the browser is closed. They are not stored on your hard disk and are usually used to track the pages you visit in order to personalise the information extracted about this specific visit of yours.
  * Persistent cookies – these Cookies are stored on your hard disk until you delete them or they expire. They can be used, for example, to store your preferences of the visited website.

Acceptance

By using this website, you agree that Allcatalogues.co.za can store Cookies on your computer or mobile device.

**How do we use Cookies?**

The cookies of Allcatalogues.co.za web pages have important functions: they register the user’s preferred settings in using the specific website and provide personalised and better web content. When you shop online, for example, they store the items you have placed in the shopping cart and when you use our online support they give you the option to select a device and find the answers to your questions as fast as possible.

Another type of Cookies helps us understand how customers use our websites. This information supports us in optimising our online projects. These Cookies can show the time and duration of use as well as provide us with information about the way users browse our website. It is important to note once again that Cookies do not store your personal details. That is why our Marketing Department, working with the web analysis tools, is not able to identify you personally. In this case, the important facts we receive are of the following type: how much time it takes for a given page to load or what type of information is most searched for by the users, as well as the time and duration of use and information about the way the users browse the website. These Cookies are also useful for us whenever the website does not work properly. In such cases the Cookies helps us localise the problem and solve it.

We use the third type of Cookies in order to decide where to position our online ads and to define their efficiency. Their task is to inform us when any of our advertisements, placed on another website (e.g. Google, Yahoo, etc.), forward a user to the Allcatalogues.co.za website. Same as with the other two types, this type of Cookie does not collect your personal information or data.

**Types of Cookies used by Allcatalogues.co.za**

The Cookies we use may be divided in two categories. The first one includes the Cookies placed by us or “first-party Cookies”, and the second one – Cookies placed by our partners, or “third-party Cookies”.

**First-Party Cookies**

The basic functionality of our website depends mainly on the Cookies placed by us. They include also web analytical Cookies assisting us in getting the number of users visiting a specific website as well as in storing our users’ preferences, in tracing their path and activity on our website and, last but not least, in storing the items selected by the customers of our website.

**Third-Party Cookies**

These are the Cookies placed by third parties, or selected partners of ours. They do not collect or send any personal information about you either. Online questionnaires or live chat helping you to get all your questions answered are some of the beneficial services they activate. The advertising networks we use can also place Cookies helping them in gathering useful information in placing our online ads to the most appropriate places.

**Social Networks Cookies**

You can use social networks such as Facebook and Twitter to share specific pages of our websites. It is useful to know that such social networks place their own Cookies. That is why you may want to search their websites for more information regarding their Cookie Policy.

**Cookies Management**

The most popular web browsers give you the option to manage the Cookies. You can choose to accept or reject all Cookies or only some specific types.

What happens when you reject all Cookies?

You will be able to use some parts of our websites, including many of the pages containing information regarding the last Allcatalogues.co.za products. But if you reject all Cookies, some useful sections will not be working. You will not be able, for example, to use our online support or to go shopping. Apart from that, you will not be able to register for the Allcatalogues.co.za online warranty or to log into your account.

How to manage Cookies in different web browsers?

For more information regarding the way you manage Cookies in the basic web browsers, please, use the links below. These pages are not websites of Allcatalogues.co.za and all of them are written in English (most of them, however, provide the option to choose from different languages).

PC computer and Mac computer

Mobile devices

(The different Blackberry devices may differ in terms of instructions, but the link above contains information about all Blackberry manuals.) In case you use a web browser that is not mentioned above, please, check its documentation or the online help for more information.

Not sure which browser you have? Find out:

PC computer: open the web browser and click on “Help” in the upper part of the browser window. Then select “About”. Information about your web browser should pop up on your screen.

Mac computer: open the web browser and click its name in the upper part of the screen (e.g. “Safari“ or “Firefox“). Then select “About”. Information about your web browser should pop up on your screen.

Mobile device: Check the name of the application you open when surfing the Internet.

More Information about Cookies Management

[www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) is a useful resource containing very detailed information regarding Cookies and methods for their management.

In case you wish to learn more about how to stop redirecting and behavioural retargeting, visit the Network Advertising Initiative at the following address [www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

**You do not want to receive cookies?**

If you don't want us to use cookies or you you do not want to receive them, when you visit Allcatalogues.co.za, you can also install the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

Links to External Websites

Please, note that Allcatalogues.co.za is not responsible for the content of external websites. We update our website links on a regular basis, but sometimes the content of external sites may not be updated or accurate.

**3\. What data we collect and why.**

We collect usage data such as the IP address of your computer, the time and date, the amount of data transferred, the website from which you came to our site, and information about the operating system and browser you use.

**This website uses:**

-          **Facebook and Google+ plug-ins:**

Our website uses the plug-ins of the social networking sites, especially the “Like”-button. The website of the provider, i.e. Facebook.com, is managed by Facebook Inc., 1601 South California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. The plug-ins are usually marked with the Facebook logo.

In addition to the Facebook plug-ins, we use these of Google+ as well. (provider: Google Inc., Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA).  The following explanations regarding Facebook are also valid for Google+ with the respected differences. If you visit our website, your browser will create a link to the Facebook servers, the information will be transmitted to Facebook, even if you haven’t been logged in your profile and regardless of the fact that you haven’t really activated the plug-in, i.e. you haven’t clicked it.

If you’ve been logged in your Facebook profile during your stay on our website, Facebook can connect the access to our website with your profile. If you click the “Like”-button, your action will be transmitted to Facebook and the data will be stored there, so you can share what you “Like”-d with your friends on Facebook. We can’t regulate the nature and the amount of the transmitted to Facebook data. Furthermore, we don’t know exactly what data of yours  is transmitted to Facebook and for what purposes it is used by Facebook. Your IP address is transmitted and – according to Facebook – information about the website you’ve visited, the date and time of your visit, and other information about your browser. You may find more information regarding Facebook on <http://www.facebook.com/help/?faq=186325668085084>.

If you don’t want Facebook to connect your visit to our website with your Facebook profile you must log out of it before visiting our site.

\-           ** **Facebook Connect****

Facebook Connect is application which allows to our users to interact on our website through their Facebook account. The main functionality is to make our site access much more easier for the users.

\-           ** **Facebook Custom Audience****

** ** Facebook Custom Audience is a type of audience thet we create of our existing customers on Facebook. With that Custom Audiences, we can reach customers that we already know with ads on Facebook.  

\-           ** **DoubleClick****

We make use of Google DoubleClick service to measure the effectiveness and performance of our online marketing campaigns. Let us explain you how it works.

For example, DoubleClick uses cookie IDs to keep a log of which ads show to which browsers. When it’s time to serve an ad to a browser, DoubleClick can use the browser’s cookie ID to check which DoubleClick ads have already been delivered to that particular browser. That's how we use them to avoid showing ads that the user has already seen. We don't sold the colected data on third parties and beside that DoubleClick cookies does't contain any personally identifiable information.

-          **Newsletter**

To subscribe to our newsletter you only have to provide us with your e-mail. You don’t have to create a personal profile.

You can unsubscribe at any time. Your e-mail will be deactivated immediately from our list and you won’t be receiving our newsletters.

If you are an Email-User, Allcatalogues.co.za may use your user ID in combination with Google Universal Analytics and Google Analytics to track and analyze the pages of the Services you visit.  We do this only to better understand how you use the Website and the other Services, with a view to offering improvements for all Allcatalogues.co.za users; and to tailor our business and marketing activities accordingly, both generally and specifically to you. Google Analytics cookies do not provide Allcatalogues.co.za with any Personal Information.

\-          **Google Adwords Conversion (Advertising)**

Conversion tracking is a tool that provides publishers whit information about what happens after a customer clicks on your ads - whether they purchased a product, signed up for your newsletter, called your business, or downloaded your app.When a customer completes an action that you've defined as valuable, these customer actions are called conversions.

-          **Google Analytics**

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies, text files stored on your computer, to help the website analyze how users utilize the site. The information generated by the cookies about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. We’d like to state that Google Analytics on this site contains the code „gat._anonymizeIp();” which guarantees the anonymous recording of IP addresses (IP masking). In order to sustain the anonymity of IP addresses visiting this site, your IP address is shortened by Google within the EU and EEA. Only in exceptional cases the full IP address is transferred to a Google server in the USA and shortened there.

You may find more information regarding Google privacy policy on this address: https://www.google.com/intl/coza/policies/

\-           **Google Analytics for Display Advertisers – cookie usage**

For customers that are using Google Analytics' Display Advertiser features, such as remarketing, a third-party DoubleClick cookie is used in addition to the other cookies described in this document for just these features. For more information about this cookie, visit the Google Advertising Privacy FAQ.

\-           **Google AdSense**

Google uses advertising companies to post ads when you visit our website. Google uses cookies to post ads on this site. Users can disable the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and agreeing to the privacy policy of the content network. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other websites (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. For more information, click [here](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/2839090?hl=en).

\-           **Google Analytics for Display Advertisers – cookie usage**

For customers that are using Google Analytics' Display Advertiser features, such as remarketing, a third-party DoubleClick cookie is used in addition to the other cookies described in this document for just these features. For more information about this cookie, visit the Google Advertising Privacy FAQ.

\-           **Google Syndication**

Google Syndication is a domain owned by Google that we are using for storing and loading ad content and other resources relating to ads for Google AdSense and DoubleClick. The platform does not use any client-side tracking methods.

\-           **Google Tag Manager**

Google Tag Manager is a tool that consolidates our website tags with a single snippet of code and lets us manage everything from a web interface. Google Tag Manager is built to handle our tagging needs, and it works with Google and non-Google website tags.

-          **Remarketing.**

This site uses remarketing with Google Analytics. It helps us to show you relevant ads related to your interests outside our website. This is done thanks to the cookies. You can reject the cookie DoubleClick, by visiting Google ads management pages.

\-           ** **Hotjar****

We make use of the Hotjar service to understand how users navigate around individual pages on our site. The tool doesn't display our visitors' IP addresses within the interface wich allows all visitor data to remain anonymous.

**4\. No transmission to third parties.**

Prospecto group JSC meets all the necessary technical and organizational requirements  regarding the security of users data on this website. Your data is used only in the field of organization and is not accessible to third parties.

Prospecto group JSC does not transfer your personal data, and in particular, your e-mail addresses to third parties without your consent.
